Uh, I said let's go big. Okay, let's do
it. All right, why not? Taking up an NC4
connector. If I do something that's
wrong, you tell me. I am. Okay. You got
to strip it out first. PV wire is really
thick insulated, so you really got to
make sure you strip it well. I use
clines. If you can't find that, you get
a sharp knife and just go in a circle.
You don't want to nick that wire. You
nick that wire. You got to cut that wire
and start all over. So, you got two
connectors, male and female. You got
admin and E. We're going to make up a
negative lead hooked to the main
negative. that one to go into it.
Correct. You got a 50/50 chance. It
really doesn't matter if which one you
connect as long as you don't close the
circuit. It does matter on your
connector. Yes. Connectors in two
different sizes. Yes. Two different
connectors. One is big and one is
little. The big one goes in the little
one and the little one goes in the big
one. Make sure you put the grommet in
the right way. Very simple problems, but
if you do it wrong, it it [__] your
whole system up. It take you forever to
find. Reason I cut it short. Don't want
it to go up into that little channel. If
it goes up in there, it can arc out.
Okay. I would put this guy in here
first. Then you
I bet you that thing common sense test.
Nope. That guy ain't coming off. This
goes on first. So the big one goes in
the mail, right?
If it clicks, it fits. If it does not
click, you'll [__] something up.
These are permanent. Once you put it on,
it's on. I don't know if y'all have
these. These are my faves. You got these
little yellow guys. You can take it
apart and use it to really crank your
[__] down. See the groove? It's wide and
then it goes in. So, we literally So,
what did you find? 20 bucks. Was 20
bucks. 20. I'll find it. I bought it
online. I'll show you. I'll get it for
you. That's all our voltage. All right.
Go around it like that, too. Want you to
look at that. Make sure I cut it off
proper.
Just train it in there. You want it to
get just thinking about going the right
way. Don't put a lot of pressure on it,
but hold it. Yeah. Mhm.
See, good stuff. Hey, one for one. I
heard it. There it went. Tighten it up.
That really the most the hardest thing
you need to know. I'm f to [__] y'all up
again with this multimeter. You don't
have to set it. Detects everything. AC
DC from 12 volt to 300 volt. Hey, watch.
It owns out automatically. Go over there
and it'll test all this voltage. You can
put it right to AC. Everything
[__] automated. Hey, very smart.
Very helpful. Hey, just this scene out
here with all the panels in the Komodo
is crazy, man. Dude, this is an
insulated mug. Somebody going to have to
change that one. Look at that. 44 volts.
That's what we're expecting, right?
Yeah. Around 42. Let's check this one,
guys. Damn. All the All these have to be
Well, yeah, cuz they're all the mail.
Hey, maybe they're compatible. Maybe we
ain't even got to Yeah. Just put this
mail in here and it works. [__] Well,
let's just How you How you taking [__]
out, though? Well, man, we couldn't
That's the thing. We couldn't test it
because
Oh, okay. This tool. Sorry, guys. I had
us wasting time, man. I couldn't test
it, and I didn't even think to do that,
Julie. You know, sometimes you're so
close to something that you can't really
see it. You know what I'm saying? Why be
in here geeking? Oh, it didn't work. Cut
that [__] off. I know this one works.
You know what we need to do? We ought to
sell the solar tool belt that has
everything you need for solar and the
belt. Everything. Just Just buy this one
belt. Cost 200 bucks. The same [__] I
use. And belt.
Damn. Got a ring to it. Fails belt.
Let's do it. Hey, the Fails belt. 87.
Why does it say negative? That's how you
check if the polarity is correct. Watch.
Now you flip it. There you go. We were
at 42. Now we're at 87. What should we
see here? Should be over 100. It's like
only like 120. Oh, them [__] ain't
fitting to work. That one ain't going to
connect. Well, hold on. There it goes.
Ready? Pink. You touch yours now. Ready?
Yep. What we got? 130. 130. All right.
Now, let's clip one more together. Bro,
the only requirement for a solar panel
is that it be in the sun. Click. Click.
We should be past. We should be what?
160. We set our our solar diagram set
around 160. We're at 175 laying down on
the ground. 175 volts just like that.
How long did that take? All right, let's
do three more. I want y'all to make
three more strings just like that. I'm
going to make up three solar leads cuz
then we're going to connect all of them
in parallel and plug them in. We did all
this in series, right? Yes. Series adds
up voltage. You literally saw it go.
Amps stay the same. Amps stay constant.
Up in series, just parallel. What does
that look like? When you wire in
parallel, you connect all the negative
and all the positives together on the
same terminal. This is negative,
positive, negative, positive, negative,
positive. So, you need a bus bar to do
parallel then. Yes, you need a junction.
This is a parallel connector. All of the
negatives go here and all the positives
go here. The voltage remains constant
and the ampacity adds up. You only have
positive and negative and they only go
one way. And you have Adam and you have
Eve. They only go one way. You cannot
connect two females together. You can't
mess it up, right? You can mess it up if
you take a panel, connect in two
together, same thing leads off one
panel, boom. Don't do that. These are
called MC4 connectors. You have a male
and a female, Adam and Eve. Big one and
a little one clip together. They only go
one way. Yep. That's it. And so this is
series, right? When it's just going down
the line like this. So connecting in
series, negative to positive. 89. Okay.
Clip. Clip. 133. 13. All right. All
these panels are looking All these
panels are looking great. Good as hell.
179 180. Yep. Cooking. We need We need
four one more string of force. Very
important with solar. All your strings
have to be balanced. What is balanced?
Balance means all the same number,
wattage, rating. Can mix match with
micro inverters, but that's outside of
the scope of what we're doing today.
That's advanced solar scientisting. And
this is intro right now. All the same
panels. What are these? 400 or 420?
450s. 450s. We have four 450s wired in
series. Four 450s in series. Four 450s
and four 450s all the same. We're going
to connect all of them in parallel. We
have two inputs is we're going to
connect two on one parallel and two on
the other. The one thing they need to do
is put somewhere where you can put this
remote instead. Bro, we got that. I'll
get some Velcro and some blue. Oh [__]
Oh no. What? I didn't see a PV a blue PV
connector. Where's that meter? This is a
complete string. Now we're going to go
black to black and red to red. So we
make sure our polarity is correct. 108
105 88 85. The sun's moving right now.
97. When you're doing these panels here,
how do you know which side is positive
and negative? I have a little icon on
it.
Positive. You know what it says, but you
check with the meter. Uh-huh. Ooh, baby.
Which is which? What do you mean which
is which? Which is positive and which is
negative. Well, how can we can we just
pull up a multimeter to it to figure
out? Yeah, but that's PV in so it's not
going to be putting out voltage. I'm
going to guess we can test this one and
see if it's positive, right? And then
off of that, it'll be the same. Assume,
bro. You sent this [__] down here
without the connector. What you want to
happen? You thought we was going to be
patient. Love the [__] out of battery
Evo. Sometimes it pissed me off. If all
that stands between us and testing this
[__] off of solar is something to plug
into that, we fit. We're going to make
Yeah. And so what we have confabulated
is that we're going to take these damn
little terminal connector and we're
going to crimp them. It stabs them in
there. This part is intended to make a
secure stable connection. Let's go. This
is a 10 to 12 gauge. I mean I I hope
this will handle that much voltage.
Times the word confabulate has been
Googled before when we posted. Never
even heard that word before you. Well,
damn. Your f your ratchets are stiff as
[__] [__] God damn. This is the
difference. That guy is made for these
and that's made for MC4 connectors.
That's That's why you see I tried to use
it for that and it didn't work. But look
at that [__] Now is it coming now? Is
it coming off? No. [__] No, bro. That's
put on there with recharge strength. I'm
going tell you something. That was
fantastic. But you put it on the wrong
one.
[Music]
Wait. Oh [__] I put it on. I got Wait a
minute. Oh, look. This is Look, this is
the [__] wire. We're at 80 volts and
that's my positive on the left. We're
not getting anything there. But this is
my negative. You can see I'm reading 80
volts. Positive to negative. If I switch
it, two-step verification know you to
death. But I'll forget that sheet if I
don't do
that. Well, that's in
[Music]
there. Oh, where's that meter? Come on,
baby. We going. I got momentum. You know
what we're doing? We're checking
voltage. We're clipping together. We
have one string of red neckery right
here. 172. So we plug it in.
Connect 174. Now what are we expecting
to see here?
174. There we go. And now look that 175
right there. Look, we have a negative
value. That is because our reds and our
black. We connected all those in series
and you saw the voltage add up. Then we
connected all the series in parallel and
the voltage remains constant. I mean we
could connect it now and see if it goes.
Okay. We can hook all four of it if you
want and just go big. I said let's go
big. Okay. All right. Why not? We got
all the panels laying out. Let's do it.
175. All right. 177. All right. Oh, hold
on now. Why? Which which circuit is
that? 80 something. I went to tighten it
up and it came out. Let's check it
again. That might not be the fix, but
let's see. It definitely was [__] up.
That's it. 170. That's it. Had we wired
up an 85 vol circuit to this and plugged
it in. What would have happened? We're
connected in parallel. It would have
brought everything down, right? To 86
volts. And what would have happened when
you That's not the minimum charge for
this. The minimum is 90 volt. So, we got
nothing. You have to check your work.
It's just like math. Yeah, you have to
check your work. These bugs are fake.
179 and looking fine. Hey. All right,
move out the way, Joe. Uh,
I have to move.
Oh [__] Yeah, these start to get caught
up in there.
Check our voltage here. Make sure
everything is on. I'm going to do this.
Oh, and then check with the multi. Yeah.
To make sure that's just not negative.
At the very end, I want to plug it in.
There's some dirt in this connector.
What starts a fire? Tiny bit of
looseness that creates a small space for
electricity to jump through air. A loose
neutral causes more fires than anything
else in residential homes.
Nothing go boom. 174 correct
orientation. Positive value. Ready?
Yep. Come on, baby. Where is it? Where
is that? It's on the It's on this side
there. Look. PV power. It's starting to
move. It's going 850. Come on now. There
it is. Julian Brown. Bro, off of some
used panels and we got 2,000 watts
coming in right now, baby. We have four
strings around 40 amps is as high as you
expect to get it. You just saw 32 laying
on ground. 2200 watts coming in. If you
just kept that for 4 hours, dude, that's
10KW. Yep.
[__] Oh, this is some goddamn Harbor
Freight splice
connectors. Hey. Hey. Hey, we ain't
saying it's right, but we saying it
works. Julie, charging. Hey, go get your
welder. Plug that welder in. Let's do it
now.